-女士  -丽兹
- Ma'am? - Hi, Lizzy.
他们叫我下来
They told me to come down here.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
很好
Good.
我想见你  因为我要和瑞克出去了
I wanted to see you because I'm going on a run with Rick.
你觉得达里尔死了吗
Do you think Daryl's dead?
不
No.
他得去很远的地方取药
He had to go far away to get the medicine,
所以需要些时间
so it's gonna take a while.
我们失去了D区所有的食物
We lost all our food in cell block D,
所以我们要去找些食物
so we're gonna go look for more
和别的有用的东西
and whatever else we can find.
现在还没人死
Nobody's died yet.
还没
Yet?
我觉得很多人都会死
I think a lot of people are going to die.
总是这样
It's what always happens.
让我很难过  但是
Makes me sad, but...
至少他们能复生
at least they get to come back.
丽兹  他们复生时  他们不是...
Lizzy, when they come back, they aren't--
原来的自己
people aren't who they were.
是啊  但他们还存在
Yeah, but they're something.
还活着
They're someone.
我现在很小
I'm little now.
如果我不死  就会长大
If I don't die, I'll get big.
我还是我  但我也会不一样
I'll be me, but I'll be different.
就是这样
It's how it is.
我们都会改变
We all change.
我们都不会和原来一样
We all don't get to stay the same way we started.
丽兹  这更为复杂
Lizzy, it's more complicated--
你说我很软弱  我不是
You said I was weak. I'm not.
我很坚强  所以我告诉你我的想法
I'm strong, so I'm telling you what I think.
你记得遇到危险时  我教你怎么做吗
You remember what I told you to do when there's danger?
撒丫子就跑
Run as fast as I can.
跑到安全的地方
You run and run until you're safe.
如果你或你妹妹命悬一线
And if it's your life or your sister's life,
你不能害怕杀人
you can't be afraid to kill.
知道吗
Understand?
知道
Yes.
你很坚强  丽兹
You are strong, Lizzy.
你会活下来的
You're gonna live.
你  你妹妹和我
You, your sister, and me--
我们都会活下去  我知道
we're gonna survive, I know it.
你的匕首呢
Where's your knife?
把T恤塞到匕首后面
Put your T-shirt behind it.
你必须能快速拔刀
You've gotta be able to get to it quickly.
好  妈妈  我是说女士
Yes, Mom. I mean ma'am.
别叫我"妈妈"
Don't call me "Mom."
那是口误
It was an accident.
别这样叫
Just don't.
好的
Okay.
怎么了
What is it?
我不怕杀行尸
I'm not afraid to kill.
我只是内心很害怕
I'm just afraid.
你不能害怕
You can't be.
如何做到呢
How?
去攻克它
You fight it.
战胜它
And fight it.
别放弃
You don't give up.
然后某天
And then one day,
你就变了
you just change.
我们都会变
We all change.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译  冰蓝
翻译  33来了
翻译  Reginamoon
翻译  重案组李Sir
翻译  卫老哥
翻译  Eowyn
翻译  送小饭
翻译  送小孩
翻译  小早  蘑菇
校对  冰蓝  米小勒  送小孩
时间轴  加森  雪贵人
时间轴  marktaotao
特效/后期  、青衣
特效/后期  吉吉
翻译/精校/总监  送小孩
行尸走肉
第四季  第四集
这条是特纳溪
This is Turner Creek,
顺着下游走几英里就到巴恩斯维尔镇了
so Barnesville must be a few miles downstream.
运气好还可以搞辆车
Sounds like our best chance at finding a new ride.
嘿  泰
Yo, Ty.
快点跟上  赶路了
Come on, let's go. Vonos.
泰
Ty.
Ty!
再往南走几英里就有小镇了
There should be a town a few miles south.
我们浪费了一整晚
Lost a whole night.
我妹妹和其他人...
My sister, everybody else--
可能都死了
they're probably dead.
继续走总有希望
Well, it helps to keep moving.
不  没有
No, it doesn't.
玛姬本来想跟来的
Maggie wanted to come, you know.
总得有人留守  照顾大家
Someone had to stay back, watch over things.
你是指让你信任的人留下
Someone you trust, you mean.
他们本来也会被自己的血液呛死
They would have drowned in their own blood.
他们备受煎熬  我解脱了他们
They were suffering. I made it quick.
我们得处理掉尸体
We needed the bodies gone.
以防止病毒扩散
We needed to stop it from spreading.
他们是当时唯一被感染的人
They were the only ones who were sick.
活着就是隐患
They were a threat.
我这么做是为了救大家
I was trying to save lives.
我迫不得已  总有人得站出来
I had to try. Somebody had to.
也许吧
Maybe.
是碧石吗
Is that jasper?
成色不错  很衬你的眼睛
It's a good color. Brings out your eyes.
理查德小姐在A区  我们走的时候
When Miss Richards went into A block, we were leaving.
她让我帮她留意
Asked me to keep a lookout.
我打算用这个给她爸爸做墓牌
I'm gonna use it for her old man's marker.
监狱的人你都认识吗
You know all them back there?
在那里一待就是几个小时
You stay in one place more than a couple hours,
能记住的东西连自己也佩服
you'd be surprised what you pick up.
抱歉  车很脏
你觉得他们会回来吗
Think they're coming back?
挡风玻璃很干净  被擦过
Windshield's clean, wiped down.
停在这里不会超过一天  可能两天
Can't have been here more than a day, maybe two.
你是说达里尔和其他人
You mean Daryl and the others.
我们此行是以防万一  是吗
That's what this is, right?
以防他们回不来
In case they don't?
在他们回来前  我们先这样
Until they do. That's what this is.
搜索药柜  急救箱
Medicine cabinets, first aid kits--
任何能够帮到赫谢尔的东西
anything that could help Hershel.
我们速战速决
We get in, we get out.
能吃的东西都带走
And if we can eat it, we take it.
无铅柴油
.
→HELL[地狱]
你看见什么了吗
You see something?
不清楚  可能吧
I don't know. Maybe.
我们得找一块新电池
We gotta find us a new battery.
里面有些朋友
Got some friends inside.
走吧
Come on.
我们清出一条路  看看有多少行尸
Let's clear a path, see how many we got.
伙计  放轻松
Hey, man, go easy.
我们不清楚里面的情况
We don't know what we're dealing with.
泰尔西
Tyreese!
泰
Ty!
泰  放开它
Ty, let him go.
你为什么不放开它
Why the hell didn't you let go?
卡萝尔
Carol!
没事的
Whoa, whoa. It's cool.
我们是活人
We're-- we're cool.
我们有水果
We have fruit.
我们有杏  桃子
Yeah, we got apricots, peaches.
给  接着
Here, catch.
或者  别接
Or, you know, don't.
-怎么弄的  -转角处有个温室
- How'd this happen? - Greenhouse around the corner.
我们想找个地方住一晚
We were looking for a place to crash.
温室房顶坏了
The roof's broken now and
一直被雨水滋润  所以全是水果
it's been getting rain, so it's full of fruit.
我们在那里待了一天
We were there about a day
然后嗜皮者出现了
and the skin-eaters showed up.
很扫兴  兄弟
Killjoys, man.
它们毁了这个世界
Jackin' it up for the whole world.
以前我还觉得所有人都是混蛋
I thought everybody was an asshole before this all went down.
但现在我喜欢人了
Now I love people.
活着的人
You know-- people who are alive.
怎么受伤的
How did it happen?
它们从门口进来
When they were coming in through the door,
我往外爬的时候绊倒了
I tripped crawling out the other side.
把玻璃拔出来了  但是我的肩膀
Pulled the glass out, but my shoulder--
还是疼得要死
it still hurts like a bitch.
脱臼了
It's dislocated.
你能弄好吗
Can you fix it?
过来  躺下
Here, lay on your back.
好了  往边上挪一挪
Okay, scooch over to the edge.
抬起手臂
Just hold your arm...
抓住这个袋子
Grab ahold of this bag.
抓住了
Hold on.
-坚持住  -不行了  好疼
- And keep holding on. - No, that hurts.
坚持住
Keep holding.
我做不到  我不行了
I can't, I can't.
坚持住
Keep holding.
坐起来
Sit up.
好了吗
Is it...
好了
Yeah.
还会酸痛几天
It's gonna be sore for a few days.
离开了温室之后  你们就来这儿了吗
After the greenhouse, you came here?
是的  我们以为这儿挺安全的
Yeah. We thought it was clear.
我们没发现那些穿着睡衣的活死人
We missed the deadie in the PJs,
所以不得已冲进了卫生间躲着
so we dove into the bathroom.
那在我们来之前
So how long were you up there
你们在里面躲了多久了
till we showed up?
大概两天吧
Like, two days.
这儿只有一个行尸  你们还有枪
There was just one. You had guns.
我们只剩大约十二发子弹了
We have about 12 bullets.
而我们一般得开五六枪才能放到一个
It usually take us about five or six to bring one of them down.
但是你们有刀子啊
But you have knives.
那要怎样  一刀扎进脑子里吗
To what, stab it in the head?
是的
Yeah.
大约一周前我们和伙伴们分散了
We got separated from our crew about a week ago.
因为只剩我们俩了  所以我们一直小心翼翼的
Been trying to play it safe since it's just the two of us.
-我的腿伤了  所以必须谨慎  -是啊
- I have to with my leg. - Yeah.
我们当时住在一个难民营
We were at a refugee center together
结果那儿起火了
and there was a fire.
人们从我身上踏了过去
People were just trampling over me.
真是群混蛋
Assholes.
萨姆救了我一命
Sam saved my life.
我们之前并不认识彼此
We didn't know each other before.
虽然我的腿没治好  但也算伤愈了
It didn't heal right, but it healed.
而且我们找到了彼此
And we found each other.
受伤也值得了
It was worth it.
接下来你俩要去哪里
Where are you two headed next?
我们会不停地换地方
We just keep moving.
我们不会等到一个地方待不下去了才走
We haven't been waiting for places to go bad.
我是说  那已经行不通了
I mean, it's getting a little old.
你们看起来还不错
You guys look all right.
你们的落脚地什么样
What's your setup like?
嗜皮者
The "Skin-eaters"?
我们叫它们行尸
We call them walkers.
瑞克的三个问题
你们杀过多少行尸
How many have you killed?
欢迎来到乔治亚州  生人勿扰
跟上
Come on.
找到了
Here we go.
电池看起来挺干
Hmm, cells look pretty dry.
补点蒸馏水就行了
A little distilled water will clear that right up.
你应该放手的
You should have let him go.
说得好像你很懂似的
The hell you know about it, huh?
-你他妈是专家吗  -不是
- You the damn expert? - No.
我只是不想看你送死
I just don't want to see you die.
这是你的目的吗
Is that what you're trying to do?
你知道自己在干什么吗
Do you even know what you're trying to do?
我知道你很恼火
I know you're pissed.
你有理由愤怒
And you have every reason to be.
但愤怒只会让你变得愚蠢
But anger makes you stupid.
而愚蠢会害死你自己
Stupid gets you killed.
你难道不是还对总督愤怒吗
Aren't you still angry about the Governor?
对他的所作所为
What he did?
如果他现在在这儿的话
If he was here right now,
我会把他砍成两截
I'd cut him in two.
因为他罪有应得
'Cause that's how it needs to be.
但我不愤怒
But I'm not angry.
我曾经愤怒
I was.
那你为什么还要出去找他
Then why are you still going out looking for him?
我不知道
I don't know.
真恶心
That's puke.
防冻冷却液
那些蔓藤里的傻瓜是自杀的
Those douchebags in the vines took themselves out,
手拉着手
holding hands--
高唱圣歌
kumbaya style.
他们希望死后跟生前一样相聚
They wanted to go out together same as they lived.
这算傻么
That make them douchebags?
算  他们本能逃生的
It does if they could have gotten out.
所有人都会努力求生
Everybody makes it,
直到他们撑不下去
till they don't.
如今人们就像多米诺骨牌
People nowadays are dominoes.
他们也许只是不想看着同伴倒下
What they did, maybe it's about not having to watch them fall.
好吧
Right.
快来
Come on.
该拿的差不多都拿了
We got about all we're gonna get here.
我们该走了
We should move on.
我们通过你的测试了吗
So, did we pass your test?
我们在向北八英里的一座监狱扎营
We're in a prison eight miles north.
如果你们跟我们回去
If you come back with us,
我们无法保证你们的安全
we can't guarantee your safety.
我们那里爆发了一种流感
There's an illness, a flu.
情况非常糟
It's bad.
我们已经失去了很多人
We've lost a lot.
-还有孩子  -你们俩的孩子吗
- Kids, too. - Yours?
不是  谢天谢地
No, thank God.
但我有一个姑娘被感染了
But one of my girls, she's got it.
-很抱歉  -她很坚强  会挺过去的
- I'm sorry. - She's strong. She'll make it.
你们有护栏和围墙
You got fences and walls?
那我们愿意加入
We're in.
对  让我们做什么都行
Yeah, whatever you need us to do.
现在  你们就在这待着
For now, sit tight.
天黑前我们会回来接你们
The two of us will circle back for you before dark.
或者你们可以帮忙搜索一下周围的房子
Or you could help us sweep the rest of this neighborhood.
没问题  我可以去看看温室
We can do that. I can check the greenhouse,
如果没什么情况  我就多摘点水果
see if it's clear, bring back more fruit.
我也可以去搜索一些房子
And I can hit some of the houses.
谢谢你们愿意帮忙
Well, it's nice of you to offer,
但你的肩膀还
but your shoulder's barely--
只要我这边胳膊不用力就没事
As long as I don't put too much weight on this arm, I'm good.
-我还能走得挺快  -我不觉得...
- And I can still move pretty fast. - I just don't think--
我们不会冒险的
We won't take any chances.
我们会仔细观察  时机合适就动手
We'll look. And if it's cake, we'll do it.
要是不合适  我们就撤
If not, we'll just roll.
你自己看起来也不太好呢  伙计
I mean, you don't look so good yourself, man.
你惯用右手还是左手
Are you a righty or a lefty?
这能扩大我们的搜索范围
We'll cover more ground.
让我们更早回去
The sooner we get back...
你没法守着我们
You can't carry us, man.
-那样行不通  -拜托  我们想帮忙
- It doesn't work that way. - Please, we want to help.
只要你们鸣枪  我们立刻就赶回来
You fire a shot, we'll come running.
我们两小时后还在这里碰面
Let's meet back here in two hours.
你会需要这个的
You'll need this.
你从没提起过以前所在的队伍
You never told us about the group you were with before.
哪一队
Which one?
跟你说  你在路上碰到我的时候
You know, when you found me out on that road,
我差一点就走开了
I almost kept walking.
为什么
Why is that?
因为我看够了一幕幕惨剧
'Cause I was done being a witness.
前后两次  跟两支不同的队伍
Two times, two different groups.
我都是唯一的幸存者
I was the last one standing.
好像我就必须一次次见证这些
Like I was supposed to see it happen over and over,
就像诅咒一样
like it's some kind of curse.
当你一个人在寂静的世界生存...
But, when it's just you out there with the quiet...
晚上只有喝上一瓶
used to be I'd drink a bottle of anything
才能闭眼昏睡
just so I could shut my eyes at night.
我以为在监狱里  有人群陪伴会容易些
Figured the prison, the people, thought it'd be easier.
那次去基地搜索  我纯粹是为了自己
The run to the Big Spot, I did it for me.
总得要有点事干
You gotta keep busy.
不  我去是为了弄瓶酒
No. I did it so I could get me a bottle.
什么酒都行
Of anything.
我把酒拿起来  握在手里
I picked it up, I held it in my hand,
但最终我又放下了
but I put it down.
我放下酒瓶时太用力
I put it down so hard
整个房顶都跟着塌了下来
it took the whole damn shelf with it.
所以才引来了行尸
That's what brought on the walkers,
所以扎克才会死
and that's what got Zack killed.
瞎扯
That's bullshit.
你进车里试试发动引擎吧
Why don't you get in there and try the engine?
就是一根红色和绿色的电线
It's a red and a green wire.
快去  又不是什么高科技
Go on. It ain't rocket science.
踩点油门
Give it some gas.
萨沙和我选了那个基地
Sasha and me picked that spot.
他带你一起去的
He took you with us.
没人能预见到那些事
There ain't no way anybody could've known.
你不再是独自一人
You ain't gonna be standing alone,
再也不会  咱们走吧
not no more. Let's go.
起码都过期了一年
It's all expired by at least a year.
还是拿着吧  让赫谢尔决定他要什么
Better to take it. Let Herschel decide what he needs.
你觉得这样做对吗
Did you think it was right?
让那些孩子跟我们一起回去
Letting those kids come back with us?
这样做才人道
I think it was the humane thing to do.
但你觉得这样对吗
But did you think it was right?
看看我们
Look at us.
翻箱倒柜  希望
Digging through drawers, hoping that...
借着一些止咳糖和消毒剂
a couple of cough drops and some disinfectant might be the difference
让人多活几个小时
between dying and living a couple of more hours.
如果他们能帮我们渡过难关
If they're strong enough to help us survive this thing,
那么没错  我认为你的决定是正确的
yeah, I think you made the right call.
如果不行呢
And if they're not?
希望他们能吧
Let's hope they are.
是啊
Yeah.
瑞克
Rick...
我杀了两个人  可你只字不提
I killed two people and you haven't said a word about it.
你想让我说什么
What do you want me to say?
重点不是你说什么
It's not about what you say.
而是要去面对现实
It's about facing reality.
现实总是来势汹汹  而一次又一次
It always comes for us and over and over again
我们唯有面对现实  才得以生存
we face it so that we can live.
-这只是为了我们能生存  -没错
- So that we can live. - That's right.
归根结底就是这一目标而已
That's what it always comes down to.
你可以当农民  瑞克
You can be a farmer, Rick.
但不能只是个农民
You can't just be a farmer.
你是位出色的领袖
You're a good leader.
比我想象的还要出色
Better than I probably gave you credit for.
我从没杀过两个自己人
I never murdered two of our own.
只有一个
Just one.
他要杀了我
He was gonna kill me.
他们也是
So were they.
他们会把我们所有人都杀死
They were gonna kill all of us.
这你没法知道
You don't know that.
如果你认为这样能救朱迪思或卡尔
If you thought it would save Judith or Carl,
你会这样做吗
would you have done it then
还是回去种庄稼
or would you have just gone back to your crops
希望一切都会没事
and hoped it'd all be okay?
你没必要喜欢我的所作所为  瑞克
You don't have to like what I did, Rick.
我也不喜欢
I don't.
你只要接受就行了
You just accept it.
看起来我们快到了
Looks like we're getting closer.
我们要找的楼房就在前面
The building we want is just up ahead.
学习资料中心
走吧  走吧
Come on. Come on.
好了  咱们速战速决
All right, let's make this quick.
就是这些
There you go.
还有这个
Here.
走
Come on.
去街对面的房子看看
Let's hit the houses across the street.
等会
Hold on.
你怎么会治肩膀脱臼呢
How'd you put his shoulder back before?
跟赫谢尔学的吗
You learn that from Herschel?
网上学的
Internet.
这样总比骗急诊护士说我第三次从楼梯上跌落好些
It's easier than telling an ER nurse I'd fallen down the stairs a third time.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事  自己动手丰衣足食
Don't be. Just fixed what needed fixin'.
我其实还说服过自己  和他一起生活是快乐的
I actually convinced myself I was happy with him.
想到至少不是孤苦伶仃
Which wasn't all that hard to do
这事也就显得没那么困难了
considering my idea of happiness then was just not being alone.
起码能过个像样的日子
Made a decent living.
他有心的时候  还是很有魅力的
He was charming when he wanted to be,
尤其是那些他酩酊大醉后醒来的早上  他会...
especially those mornings after he'd come home piss-drunk and...
我太傻了
Stupid.
愚蠢透顶
那时我觉得自己无法坚强起来
I didn't think I could be strong.
感觉完全做不到
I didn't know I could.
可我现在做到了
I already was.
你为什么都不说她的名字
Why don't you say her name?
她已经死了  瑞克
She's dead, Rick.
索菲亚
Sophia.
死了
Dead.
已成昨日之梦
Somebody else's slideshow.
有时早晨醒来我会期望洛莉还在
Some mornings I still wake up half-expecting Lori to be there.
提醒我去接卡尔放学
Reminding me to pick up Carl after school
叫我准备吃早餐
or telling me breakfast is ready.
每周日她都会给我们做烤薄饼  简直...
Every Sunday she'd make us these pancakes that were just...
难吃到要死
godawful.
面粉和得也不对劲儿
Clumps of flour that weren't mixed in right.
问题是...
Thing was...
她自己也知道难吃
she knew it was bad.
那她为什么还做啊
Why'd she keep at it?
她就是...
Well...
希望跟别人家一样
she wanted us to be the kind of family
周末吃顿薄煎饼才像一家人
that ate pancakes on Sunday.
我们该回去了
We should get back.
萨姆应该在等了
Sam is probably waiting.
所有叫"西林"或者"林"的药  通通都拿走
Anything ending with -cillin or -cin, C-I-N, grab it.
把药溶进点滴里
We'll dissolve the pills in the IVs,
直接静脉注射
put 'em right into the bloodstream.
剂量不太好定  但是考虑到拖延的时间太长
Dosage will be tricky but considering the time we lost...
你们怎么样
How'd you do?
输液袋  输液管  夹子  连接头都有了
Bags, tubes, clamps, connectors.
-单子上的都有了  -你们这边呢
- Everything on the list. - What about y'all?
都搞定了
Yeah, we got it all.
都好了
Yeah. We're good.
好的  走吧
All right, let's roll.
出口
前面
Up ahead.
门坏了关不上
Hey! Door's busted.
挡住
Oh. Hold up.
楼梯
这边
There.
-有多少  -看不出来
- How many? - I can't tell.
-我们可以干掉它们  -不要
- We can take 'em. - No!
它们被感染了  和监狱里一样
They're infected. Same as at the prison.
我们干掉它们  血溅满身  再吸进去
We fire at 'em, get their blood on us, breathe it in.
我们大老远来这不是为了被感染的
We didn't come all this way to get sick.
我们怎么知道它们是不是一样呢
How do we know the ones in there aren't any different?
-我们不知道  -总得想办法出去
- We don't. - Well, it's gotta change sometime.
准备好了吗
Ready?
动手
Do it!
快走
Come on.
太久了
It's been too long.
我们应该再给他点时间
We should give him a couple more.
他也许没事
He might be fine.
真的有可能
He really might be.
但是已不重要了
But it doesn't matter...
因为他现在不在这  而我们得走了
because he's not here... and we have to go.
可惜了一块好表
It was a nice watch.
-退后  -没有出口
- Back. - Don't have an exit.
我们打一个出来
Then we make one.
躲开
Get down!
-快点  快走  -跳到下面的走道上
- Come on, move it! - Jump down to the walkway below.
-它们过来了  -快走  快
- They're here! - Let's go! Go, go. Move.
鲍勃  放手
Bob, let it go.
别管了  老兄
Let it go, man.
放手吧
Just let it go.
别要那个包了  老兄
Let go of the bag, man.
你的包里没有药
You got no meds in your bag?
只有这个吗
Just this?
那天你应该直接走开
You should have kept walking that day.
不要
Don't.
就这样吧  达里尔
Just let it go, Daryl.
他做出了自己的选择
The man's made his choice.
你无法改变
Nothing you can do about it.
就这样吧
Just gotta let it go.
我不想伤害谁
I didn't want to hurt nobody.
只是为了排解那可怕的寂静
It was just for when it gets quiet.
把药拿回去之前  你要胆敢喝一口
Take one sip. When those meds get in our people,
我会打得你满地找牙
I will beat your ass into the ground.
听见了吗
You hear me?
他们也许能活下来
They might have lived.
凯伦和大卫  他们也许能活下来
Karen and David, they might have lived,
现在他们死了
and now they're dead.
你不能决定他人生死
That wasn't your decision to make.
如果泰尔西发现了
When Tyreese finds out...
他会杀了你
he'll kill you.
他差点都把我杀了
He damn near killed me over nothing.
我能应付泰尔西
I can handle Tyreese.
如果其他人知道了
When the others find out,
他们不会让你留下的
they won't want you there.
就算他们没能回来
And if they don't make it back,
就算大家都因疫病而死  只剩下我们俩
if everybody dies of this thing and it's just the two of us,
还有我的孩子  朱迪思和卡尔
with Judith and Carl-- with my children...
我也不会让你留下
I won't have you there.
瑞克  是我啊
Rick, it's me.
别人不需要知道的
No one else has to know.
我以为你不会再替大家做决定了
I thought you were done making decisions for everyone.
我这是为了自己
I'm making this decision for me.
我本可以假装一切都会好转
I could have pretended that everything was gonna be fine.
但我没有
But I didn't.
我出手了  我挺身而出
I did something. I stepped up.
我必须这么做
I had to do something.
不  你不必
No, you didn't.
我绝不会留下丽兹和米卡...
If you think I'm going anywhere without Lizzie and Mica--
你想让她们离开  跟你一起走吗
If you want them to leave, to go out there with you?
丽兹病了  米卡才十岁
Lizzie's sick. Mica is 10 years old.
她不行的
She can't.
我们会保护她们
We'll keep them safe.
你已经不再是那个害怕孤独的女人了  不再是了
You're not that woman who was too scared to be alone, not anymore.
你可以重新开始  找到其他人
You're gonna start over, find others,
不知道你过去的人
people who don't know,
你能在外面生存下去
and you're gonna survive out here.
你能的
You will.
也许吧
Maybe.
我本来准备走100号高速路
That's where I was traveling, Highway 100.
去那里需要花七小时
Then it will take about seven hours to get there.
我们需要更多汽油
We're gonna need more gas.
但我们会到的
But we'll get there.
-我们走100号高速  -听到了
- Taking Highway 100. - I heard.
你之前的话没错
You were right, what you said before.
我的确找不到他了
About the trail going cold.
我不用再出去了
I don't need to go out anymore.
很好
Good.
拿上吧
Take it.
爱德在我们结婚一周年时给我的
Ed gave this to me on our first anniversary.
拜托了
Please.
我早就该送人了
I should have given it away a long time ago.
? It was a close call ?
? Sitting in the back of the room ?
? with a ball I had thrown at you ?
? And you didn't know ?
? Close in on my black eye ?
? I feel safe at times ?
? Certain emblems ?
? Tell me it's time ?
? Cerpents in my mind ?
? Looking for your ?
? crimes ?
? Everything changes ?
? I don't want mine ?
? this time ?
? Everything changes ?